<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-09-08T10:10:21-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">Site Map</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/exercises/e4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Site Map" /><published>2020-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/exercises/e4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/exercises/e4/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;e4-site-map&quot;&gt;E4: Site Map&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a site map showing the structure and organization of a website. Also include who you think the intended audience is and what the main action or actions the site is hoping a user will accomplish. The site needs to be more than a few pages. It should multiple levels of information across multiple pages. You can create your site map in any software you choose but it needs to be done digitally. My recommendation would be to use Xd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upload a PNG of your final site map to your site and include a link to the website you made the site map for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;URL for your website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Site’s intended audience&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Site’s primary action for the user&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;PNG of your digital site map on your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;due&quot;&gt;Due Tuesday, September 15 by 10:30 ET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="exercises" /><summary type="html">E4: Site Map</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 4</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/due/due/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 4" /><published>2020-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/due/due</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/due/due/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;quiz-3&quot;&gt;Quiz 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get a 100!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-3-organization-and-naming&quot;&gt;Exercise 3: Organization and Naming&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submit a link to the exercise on Blackboard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-4-site-map&quot;&gt;Exercise 4: Site Map&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submit a link to the exercise on Blackboard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-5-wireframes&quot;&gt;Exercise 5: Wireframes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Submit a link to the exercise on Blackboard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;p13-checkpoint-3&quot;&gt;P1.3: Checkpoint 3&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pages linked together and styled, link submitted to the first page on Blackboard&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="due" /><summary type="html">Quiz 3 Get a 100!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Organization and Naming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/exercises/e3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Organization and Naming" /><published>2020-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/exercises/e3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/exercises/e3/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;e3-organization-and-naming&quot;&gt;E3: Organization and Naming&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;File naming and organization are important parts of making sure your files are easy to find both visually and while writing links. Download this zip file and you will find there is a simple site with a terrible file structure. Rename these files something clear and simple and then organize them into a nice folder structure. The site has a main page and then 3 sub pages for an about page, a menus page, and a gallery page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have organized and renamed the files, take a screenshot of the new structure and post it to your site (Atom’s sidebar is a great view). If you cannot get a view where all the files and folders are shown in one folder, take multiple screenshots or position multiple folders on the screen to show the structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Folders and files appropriately named&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Folders and files appropriately organized&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screenshot(s) of folder and file structure and names on your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;due&quot;&gt;Due Tuesday, September 15 by 10:30 ET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="exercises" /><summary type="html">E3: Organization and Naming</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Wireframes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/exercises/e5/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Wireframes" /><published>2020-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/exercises/e5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/exercises/e5/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;e5-wireframes&quot;&gt;E5: Wireframes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create two wireframes for the home page of the site you used for your site map. The first wireframe should be created from the site as it looks on your computer (desktop size). The second wireframe should be created from the site as it looks on your phone (mobile size). You can create both of them sketched on paper, both digitally, or one of each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upload your wireframes to your site and include a link to the website you made the site map for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A desktop wireframe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A mobile wireframe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two image files on your website&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;due&quot;&gt;Due Tuesday, September 15 by 10:30 ET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="exercises" /><summary type="html">E5: Wireframes</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 3</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/due/due/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 3" /><published>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/due/due</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/due/due/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;quiz-2&quot;&gt;Quiz 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a 100&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-2-make-the-grid&quot;&gt;Exercise 2: Make the Grid&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring your five image files with you to class&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;p12-checkpoint-2&quot;&gt;P1.2: Checkpoint 2&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content marked up in 10 pages, link to your project 1 folder on GitHub posted in your Critique Forum thread, P1.2 assignment submitted with “posted” in the comments on Blackboard&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="due" /><summary type="html">Quiz 2</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Make the Grid</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/exercises/e2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Make the Grid" /><published>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/exercises/e2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/exercises/e2/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-2-make-the-grid&quot;&gt;Exercise 2: Make the Grid&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using XD or other approved design software make 5 artboards that are 1440 pixels wide by 3000 pixels tall. On each artboard create a grid that could be used to layout a website. The grid does not need rows, only columns. Once you have 5 different grids start adding some “content” to your pages. The content should be shapes (squares, rectangles, circles) that could represent images, icons, text, etc. Some shapes should be tall, some shapes should be short, some should be wide, and some should be narrow. The grid should be your guide for how your shapes line up and fit on the page. Do not ignore the grid. Keep in mind ideas about space and that every pixel of the page does not need to be filled. If you need a little help starting, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;/tutorials/2-point-1&quot;&gt;2.1 tutorial&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 png files at 1440px wide by 3000px tall&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Layouts use only shapes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Layouts use different grids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;due&quot;&gt;Due Tuesday, September 08 by 10:30 ET&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="exercises" /><summary type="html">Exercise 2: Make the Grid</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Intro to Xd</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2-point-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Intro to Xd" /><published>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2%20point%201</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2-point-1/">&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will go through some of the basic features of Adobe Xd and help with your file setup for  &lt;em&gt;E2: Make the Grid&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-downloadinstallopen-adobe-xd&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step1&quot;&gt;Step 1: Download/Install/Open Adobe Xd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you don’t have Adobe Xd yet you can download it &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adobe.com/products/xd.html?promoid=PYPVQ3HN&amp;amp;mv=other&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Xd should be free but I think you will need an Adobe account to use the program. Once you have it downloaded, install it and open it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-create-a-new-document&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step2&quot;&gt;Step 2: Create a New Document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you open up Xd you should be presented this screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step2a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of Xd welcome screen&quot; title=&quot;Step 2a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this screen look at the top row of sizes and in the “Custom Size” option type 1440 for the width, 3000 for the height, and then hit enter. The base unit for Xd is pixels, so unless otherwise specified, numbers are pixels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step2b.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of Xd artboard&quot; title=&quot;Step 2b&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you see the artboard you just created you can double click on the text at the top left of the artboard that says “custom-1” and change the name. Not entirely necessary but a good habit to get in as you build more complex sites in Xd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more thing you might want to change is the “Viewport Height” option in the right sidebar under “Scrolling”. This is probably set to 3000 as the default and I would suggest moving it to 900. What this does is adjust the height that Xd previews when you hit the play icon in the top right. Not so useful for Exercise 2 but very useful for designing actual sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step2c.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of Xd vertical height option&quot; title=&quot;Step 2c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, save the document before you move on to the next step. Adobe wants you to use the cloud to save your documents so if you want to use that you can go to &lt;em&gt;File &amp;gt; Save…&lt;/em&gt; or use &lt;em&gt;cmd+s&lt;/em&gt;. If you do not want to use the cloud to save your documents you can go to &lt;em&gt;File &amp;gt; Save as Local Document…&lt;/em&gt; or use &lt;em&gt;opt+shift+cmd+s&lt;/em&gt;. Save this as some version of &lt;strong&gt;e2&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;exercise2&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-create-a-grid&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step3&quot;&gt;Step 3: Create a Grid&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you start adding anything to your artboard you want to set up a grid. This is accomplished by finding the grid section of the right sidebar and checking the box next to the layout dropdown. When you check that box it will bring up options for you to create your grid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step3.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of Xd grid options&quot; title=&quot;Step 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Columns – How many columns are on the artboard. Also if you click the color to the left of the word “Columns” you can change the column color and opacity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gutter Width – The width between the columns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Column Width – The width of each column&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two Icons – The first sets the margins for the left and right equally. The second allows you to set the margins independently. Generally leave it on the first option.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play around with these options and see what happens. There is no particular number for columns, widths, or gutters so it is up to you. In Exercise 2 you will be making 5 different artboards with 5 different grids so you can see what works well for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-add-a-polygon&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step4&quot;&gt;Step 4: Add a Polygon&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This tutorial is built around Exercise 2 so the content you will be adding to your artboard are shapes. In the left toolbar there are a few different shape tools you can use — rectangle &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt;, ellipse &lt;em&gt;e&lt;/em&gt;, and polygon &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;. The rectangle and ellipse tool draw what they say and if you hold &lt;em&gt;shift&lt;/em&gt; while drawing the shape you will get a square or a circle. The polygon tool is a little different so choose that one or press &lt;em&gt;y&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default the polygon tool draws a triangle and if you hold shift it will draw and equilateral triangle. Draw a triangle on your artboard and make sure it aligns to the grid you made. The mouse should snap to the edges of the columns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step4a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of triangle on the artboard&quot; title=&quot;Step 4a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default drawing of the triangle for me is a white fill with a grey border. The options in the “Appearance” section in the right sidebar are generally the same for the rectangle and ellipse tools but the polygon tool has a few added options to control what the polygon looks like. Any option with a checkbox next to it means you can turn it on or off using that checkbox and the settings are saved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step4b.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of appearance settings&quot; title=&quot;Step 4b&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Opacity Slider – Change the opacity of the shape.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Blend Mode Dropdown – Set the blend mode for the shape.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corner Count – Adds more corners to the shape. 3 corners is a triangle, 4 is a diamond, 5 is a pentagon, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corner Radius – Rounds the corners.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Star Ratio – Bends the sides in to make star like shapes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fill – Click on the rectangle to change the color, click on “Solid Color” at the top to change the kind of fill (Gradients!).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Border – Click on the rectangle to change the color.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Border Size – Change the size of the border.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dash – Make a dashed line, pairs with the Gap option to control the look of the dashed border.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Border Alignment Icons – Aligns the border to the Inner, Outer, or Center of the stroke.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Border Cap Icons – Sets the end caps as Butt, Round, or Projecting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Corner Join Options – Sets the corner join as Miter, Round, or Bevel.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shadow – Click on the set shadow color.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shadow Options – If a shadow color is selected these options will appear, X and Y adjust the offset from the shape and B adjusts the blur of the shadow.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Background Blur – Uses shape as a mask to blur the elements behind it, three slider options to control blur amount, brightness, and effect opacity.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Object Blur – Blurs the object itself, one slider option to control blur amount.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-5-add-more-shapes&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step5&quot;&gt;Step 5: Add More Shapes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, using the grid you set up, add more shapes to create a layout. The layout will be relatively abstract and you do not need to make it feel like it could be a real webpage. Feel free to play with the appearance settings for your shapes and make sure you align the shapes to the grid. Also keep in mind white space and the idea that not ever inch of the artboard needs to be covered with shapes. Even space or proportional space between items is generally better than random space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step5a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of shapes on an artboard aligning to the grid&quot; title=&quot;Step 5a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have finished with your layout you can make another artboard by clicking the Artboard tool in the left sidebar or pressing &lt;em&gt;a&lt;/em&gt;. You can then draw the artboard just like any other shape and adjust the dimensions to 1440 x 3000 in the transform settings in the right sidebar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step5b.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of transform settings&quot; title=&quot;Step 5b&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make a different grid for this artboard and add some more shapes to it just like you did for the first artboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-6-export-artboards&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step6&quot;&gt;Step 6: Export Artboards&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have five artboards with different grids and different layouts on them, it is time to export. To export the artboards go to &lt;em&gt;File &amp;gt; Export &amp;gt; All Artboards…&lt;/em&gt;. In the pop up window choose your location and then set the “Format” to PNG, “Export For” to Design, and then click “Export All Artboards”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p1/step6.png&quot; alt=&quot;image of export settings&quot; title=&quot;Step 6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you should have five PNG files that are all 1440px by 3000px. If they are not that size you might have exported at a different size or you didn’t make your artboards the right size. In either case, go back through these steps and make sure the files are the correct size.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="tutorials" /><summary type="html">A quick tour of Adobe Xd and getting a file ready for designing.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Your Homepage</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2-point-2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Your Homepage" /><published>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2%20point%202</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2-point-2/">&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will get the homepage of your repository setup to be an archive of the work you are creating for this class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-set-up-the-html-file&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step1&quot;&gt;Step 1: Set up the HTML file&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first step is opening up your text editor, creating a new file, and saving it in the root directory of your repository as index.html. Once you have done that add in the basic HTML set up (steps 1 through 6 of &lt;a href=&quot;/tutorials/1-point-1&quot;&gt;tutorial 1.1&lt;/a&gt;). Make sure you make the text in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; element is something useful. At the end your file should look something like the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step1.png&quot; alt=&quot;basic html setup in Atom&quot; title=&quot;Step 1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-adding-content&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step2&quot;&gt;Step 2: Adding Content&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that the file is set up you can add some content. This page is going to be a list of links to the work for the class. It should have some large text at the top to give the page a title and then a bunch of links underneath that. All of this content is going to go in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;body&lt;/code&gt; element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2a-add-your-main-heading&quot;&gt;Step 2a: Add your main heading&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with a title for your page using the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/code&gt; element. Something like &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;h1&amp;gt;Michael's Work&amp;lt;/h1&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; or some other way to identify this page as yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step2a.png&quot; alt=&quot;h1 element added to body&quot; title=&quot;Step 2a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2b-add-an-unordered-list&quot;&gt;Step 2b: Add an Unordered List&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of different ways to add links to a document. Since this going to be a list of links and we want to markup the document semantically, a list element makes sense. A list with numbers next to it isn’t important here so use an unordered list element, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Add the opening tag for the unordered list on the line beneath the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/code&gt; element and the closing tag for the unordered list two lines beneath that. This leaves space to add a list item inside the unordered list. All of the elements inside the body element are at the same indent level so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step2b.png&quot; alt=&quot;ul element added to the body&quot; title=&quot;Step 2b&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2c-add-a-list-item&quot;&gt;Step 2c: Add a List Item&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The text inside a list is all contained in the list item element, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. On the line between the opening and closing tags for the unordered list, add a list item with some text that identifies this list item as Exercise 1, something like, “E1: 20 Questions”. Note that this &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;li&lt;/code&gt; element is indented another level because it is a child of the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ul&lt;/code&gt; element. Also a good time to save, &lt;span class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;cmd+s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, if you haven’t yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step2c.png&quot; alt=&quot;li element added inside the ul element&quot; title=&quot;Step 2c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2d-add-more-list-items&quot;&gt;Step 2d: Add More List Items&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Add a new line beneath the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;li&lt;/code&gt; for E1 and make an &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;li&lt;/code&gt; for E2. Repeat this process until you have list items for E1 through E5. All of these should be at the same level indent as the first &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;li&lt;/code&gt; because they are all children of the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ul&lt;/code&gt; element. Don’t forget to save.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step2d.png&quot; alt=&quot;more li elements&quot; title=&quot;Step 2d&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-add-links&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step3&quot;&gt;Step 3: Add Links&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you haven’t previewed the page yet you might want to. You should have something that looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step3.png&quot; alt=&quot;html file previewed in browser&quot; title=&quot;Step 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This works to show what the work is but the we can’t click on anything to take us to the work. To make that happen we need to add some anchor elements, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;step-3a-wrap-list-item-text-in-an-anchor-element&quot;&gt;Step 3a: Wrap List Item Text in an Anchor Element&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Put your cursor between the opening tag and the content for the first list item you have. That means the cursor should be after &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and before “E1…”. Add the opening tag for the anchor element here. At the end of the text but before the closing tag for the list item add the closing tag for the anchor element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step3a.png&quot; alt=&quot;first list item wrapped in an anchor element&quot; title=&quot;Step 3a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;step-3b-add-an-attribute&quot;&gt;Step 3b: Add an Attribute&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now there is one more part of an anchor element that needs to be added in order for the link to actually work. If you said the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;href&lt;/code&gt; attribute you are correct. In the opening tag for the anchor element but your cursor after the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;a&lt;/code&gt; and before the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Add a space and then type &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;href=&quot;#&quot;&lt;/code&gt;. The code should look like the first screenshot and if you preview the page the first list item should change to blue with an underline. If you click that link nothing will happen because it doesn’t have a path yet but it should look like the default link now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step3b1.png&quot; alt=&quot;first anchor element with href attribute&quot; title=&quot;Step 3b1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step3b2.png&quot; alt=&quot;previewed page in browser showing link styles&quot; title=&quot;Step 3b2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-add-e1-to-repository&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step4&quot;&gt;Step 4: Add E1 to Repository&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order for the link to work, Exercise 1 needs to be added to your repository. The first thing you want to do is add a folder in your repository (root directory) where the E1 file will live. There are many ways to add a folder so do it however you are comfortable. Name the folder whatever you want remembering all the rules about naming folders and files, an easy name might be &lt;strong&gt;e1&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step4.png&quot; alt=&quot;e1 folder in root directory&quot; title=&quot;Step 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the &lt;strong&gt;e1&lt;/strong&gt; folder you can add your HTML file for Exercise 1 into it. Once you add the E1 file to the &lt;strong&gt;e1&lt;/strong&gt; folder change the name of it to &lt;strong&gt;index.html&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-5-add-the-link-path&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step5&quot;&gt;Step 5: Add the Link Path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the Exercise 1 file is in the repository you can add the path to the E1 link on your homepage. You should be back in Atom looking at your &lt;strong&gt;index.html&lt;/strong&gt; file that is in your root directory. That should be the file that has the list of exercises we added earlier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find the anchor element wrapped around “E1: 20 Questions”. Delete the “#” we added when we first wrote the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;href&lt;/code&gt; attribute and change it to the correct path to get to your Exercise 1 file. Take a second to try and write it yourself and once you have something highlight the box to see what the path should be &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;e1/index.html&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A note: This path is dependent on the file and folder names this tutorial uses and the location of those files and folders. If you named something differently or put something in a different location, your path will be different than the one above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the path filled in preview the page in your browser and test out the link. Did it take you to your E1 file? If it did, great! If it didn’t, check to make sure your spelling is correct, capitalization, etc. and see if you can fix the error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step5.png&quot; alt=&quot;href value filled in for first anchor element&quot; title=&quot;Step 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the same process to add links to the other list items in your unordered list. Once you have completed them, add a folder to the repository and then add any files you need displayed in there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-6-add-css&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step6&quot;&gt;Step 6: Add CSS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The page works but it doesn’t look very good. How can you make it look better? CSS! In your repository add a &lt;strong&gt;css&lt;/strong&gt; folder. Once you have the folder make a new file in Atom and save it in your newly created &lt;strong&gt;css&lt;/strong&gt; folder as &lt;strong&gt;main.css&lt;/strong&gt;. This file will now allow you to control the look of your repository’s homepage. If you need a reminder on how CSS works make sure you have another look at the 2.3: External Style Sheets PDF on Blackboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-6a-add-styles&quot;&gt;Step 6a: Add Styles&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On line one of the newly created CSS file add a selector for something you want to style. In this case, style the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;body&lt;/code&gt; element and type &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;body {&lt;/code&gt; on line 1 and then close the style on line 3 with a closing curly bracket, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;}&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step6a1.png&quot; alt=&quot;body style in CSS&quot; title=&quot;Step 6a1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now add a declation in there (&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;property: value;&lt;/code&gt;) to change the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;background-color&lt;/code&gt; for the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;body&lt;/code&gt;. This allows a quick, easy check to see if the CSS file is correctly linked to the HTML file. Add the property &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;background-color&lt;/code&gt; with the value of &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;yellow&lt;/code&gt; to line two of the CSS file. Make sure it is indented one level because this declaration is inside the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;body&lt;/code&gt; style rule.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step6a2.png&quot; alt=&quot;changing the background color of the body in CSS&quot; title=&quot;Step 6a2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Save the CSS file and preview your main HTML file again. Did anything change? No? Any ideas why? If you guessed that the CSS file isn’t connected to the HTML file yet you would be correct!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-6b-connect-css-and-html-files&quot;&gt;Step 6b: Connect CSS and HTML Files&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To connect the two files together you need to add the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;link&lt;/code&gt; element to the HTML file. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;link&lt;/code&gt; element is an empty element that goes in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;head&lt;/code&gt; of the HTML document and must have two attributes, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rel&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;href&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open up your main &lt;strong&gt;index.html&lt;/strong&gt; file and add a new line beneath your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; element. On that line add the link element, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;link rel=&quot;#&quot; href=&quot;#&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Try and replace the “#” with the appropriate values for each attribute. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rel&lt;/code&gt; value should define the documents relationship and the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;href&lt;/code&gt; value should be the path to your css file. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;rel&lt;/code&gt; attribute – &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;rel=”stylesheet”&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;href&lt;/code&gt; attribute – &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;href=”css/main.css”&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another note: Again this path is for the file and folder names and locations of this tutorial. If you did something different, that path will not work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have the values, preview the HTML page and see if the background turned yellow. If it turned yellow that means your files are connected and you can add more styles to your CSS file to control the look of your homepage. If it didn’t turn yellow try going back through and comparing your files to the screenshots and see if you can find the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step6b1.png&quot; alt=&quot;adding the link element to the head of the HTML document&quot; title=&quot;Step 6b1&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p2/step6b2.png&quot; alt=&quot;broswer preview of HTML page showing CSS changes&quot; title=&quot;Step 6b2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-7-go-crazy&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step7&quot;&gt;Step 7: Go Crazy&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that you have a CSS file that is connected to your HTML file you can add all the styles you want. Just remember that in order to style an element in your HTML you need to target that element with the same selector. So if you want to style the list items in your HTML file, the CSS selector is going to be &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;li&lt;/code&gt;. If you want to style the level 1 heading, the CSS selector is going to be &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;h1&lt;/code&gt;. This allows you to style any HTML element that displays on the page (meaning you can’t style the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; element).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you run into something that you don’t know how to change, try Googling it as if you were asking me. “How do I change the font size in CSS?” or “How do I change the color of text HTML” or “How do I change the hover color of my links CSS?”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="tutorials" /><summary type="html">Getting the homepage of your repository setup.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Working with Images</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2-point-3/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Working with Images" /><published>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2%20point%203</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/tutorials/2-point-3/">&lt;p&gt;This tutorial will introduce the image element and how to use that element to get images to display on your pages. This tutorial will use Exercise 2 as the example for adding images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-1-open-your-repository-in-atom&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step1&quot;&gt;Step 1: Open Your Repository in Atom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start with opening up the Github App and making sure you have your repository as the Current Repository and that the Current Branch is gh-pages. If those two pieces of information are correct, click the “Open in Atom” button in the middle of the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step1a1.png&quot; alt=&quot;main Github App window&quot; title=&quot;Step 1a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should open up Atom with a screen that looks something like the below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step1a2.png&quot; alt=&quot;repository opened in Atom&quot; title=&quot;Step 1a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few notes here. If you don’t see the project panel on the left of the window you can go to &lt;span class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;View &amp;gt; Toggle Tree View&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to open it up. If you see files that start with a period, like &lt;strong&gt;.gitignore&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;.DS_Store&lt;/strong&gt; you can ignore those. They are hidden files that you probably don’t see in your repository but show up in Atom. This view is also assuming you are looking at this tutorial after finishing the 2.1 tutorial. If you have other files or folders in your repository this will look different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-2-add-a-folder-html-file-and-images&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step2&quot;&gt;Step 2: Add a Folder, HTML File, and Images&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about Atom is you can add folders and files right from the tree view in the left panel. If you right click in that panel you will see the pop out in the image below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step2.png&quot; alt=&quot;right clicking in the tree view&quot; title=&quot;Step 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2a-add-the-exercise-2-folder&quot;&gt;Step 2a: Add the Exercise 2 Folder&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that pop out click the &lt;span class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;New Folder&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; option and in the pop up that says “Enter the path for the new folder” type a folder name for your exercise 2 folder, &lt;strong&gt;e2&lt;/strong&gt; is nice, short, and descriptive. Hit &lt;span class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt; to create the folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step2a.png&quot; alt=&quot;adding a new folder in Atom&quot; title=&quot;Step 2a&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2b-add-an-html-file&quot;&gt;Step 2b: Add an HTML File&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now right click on the folder you just created but this time select &lt;span class=&quot;command&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;New File&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/span&gt;. Another pop up will appear that should already be filled with the folder name then a forward slash. If you don’t see that folder name you did not right click on the folder you just made. You want to add a new HTML file to this folder so what do you think it should be called? If you said &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;index.html&lt;/span&gt; you are correct. Type the file name and then hit enter to create the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step2b1.png&quot; alt=&quot;adding a new file in Atom&quot; title=&quot;Step 2b&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you hit enter Atom should create the file and also open it so your tree view should have a new exercise 2 folder and an HTML file inside of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step2b2.png&quot; alt=&quot;view of newly created folder and file in Atom&quot; title=&quot;Step 2b&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;step-2c-add-an-image-folder-and-images&quot;&gt;Step 2c: Add an Image Folder and Images&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once again right click on the Exercise 2 folder you created and add a new folder named &lt;strong&gt;images&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step2c1.png&quot; alt=&quot;adding an images folder in Atom&quot; title=&quot;Step 2c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that the images folder is created, add your images to that folder. You can do this a bunch of different ways but the easiest might be opening two windows with the files and dragging them from the old location to the new or copying from the old location and pasting to the new location. However you want to do it the goal is to get the 5 PNG files into the images folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step2c2.png&quot; alt=&quot;adding png files to the images folder&quot; title=&quot;Step 2c&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-3-add-in-basic-html-setup&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step3&quot;&gt;Step 3: Add in Basic HTML Setup&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your HTML file should still be open but if it isn’t make sure your HTML file in the Exercise 2 folder is open and add in the minimum HTML set up, give it a descriptive &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; and then save the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step3.png&quot; alt=&quot;html file with minimum HTML&quot; title=&quot;Step 3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-4-add-an-image&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step4&quot;&gt;Step 4: Add an Image&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To get images to display on your page you need to add the image element &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. The image element needs two attributes, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;src&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;src&lt;/code&gt; attribute is where the path to the image file goes and the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; attribute holds text to display if the image link is broken or the user is using a screen reader. The image element is also an empty element so there is no content or closing tag.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;body&lt;/code&gt; add an image element, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&quot;#&quot; alt=&quot;#&quot;&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;. Make sure it is indented one level since it is a child of the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;body&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step4a1.png&quot; alt=&quot;image element added in the body&quot; title=&quot;Step 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now replace the two attributes with the appropriate values. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;src&lt;/code&gt; – &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;src=”images/1.png”&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;alt&lt;/code&gt; - &lt;span class=&quot;spoiler&quot;&gt;alt=”shape layout 1”&lt;/span&gt;. Once again the path in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;src&lt;/code&gt; attribute is dependent on your folder and file naming. This path works for my file and folder naming, if yours is different the path needs to be different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step4a2.png&quot; alt=&quot;image element with attribute values added&quot; title=&quot;Step 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you add the other images it is worth saving the file and checking to see if everything is working in the browser. Once you have checked and verified that the image is displaying on the page, repeat this step four more times to add all of your images for Exercise 2 onto the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step4a3.png&quot; alt=&quot;all five images added to the HTML file&quot; title=&quot;Step 4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;step-5-link-to-exercise-2&quot;&gt;&lt;span id=&quot;step5&quot;&gt;Step 5: Link to Exercise 2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last step is adding a link to your main page for Exercise 2. So open up your index.html file in your root directory and add in an anchor element, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&amp;gt;...&amp;lt;/a&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; for Exercise 2. Make sure you are wrapping the text inside the list item for Exercise 2 and make sure you have an opening tag and closing tag. The value for the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;href&lt;/code&gt; attribute is dependent on your folder and file structure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/2p3/step5.png&quot; alt=&quot;adding a link to e2 on the homepage&quot; title=&quot;Step 5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure both files are saved and preview the homepage and test to see if the link for Exercise 2 is working. If it is, great! You can open up the Github App and push the changes you just made. If it isn’t working, check to make sure all your syntax, spelling, and paths are correct and try it again. If it still isn’t working, ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="tutorials" /><summary type="html">Introduction to the image element and getting images to display on your page.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Week 2</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/due/due/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Week 2" /><published>2020-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/due/due</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/due/due/">&lt;h4 id=&quot;discussion-board-1-introduce-yourself&quot;&gt;Discussion Board 1: Introduce yourself&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Posted by &lt;span class=&quot;due&quot;&gt;Friday, August 28 by 11:59pm ET&lt;/span&gt; (this is due before the due date above)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;quiz-1&quot;&gt;Quiz 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get a 100 on the quiz&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;exercise-1-20-questions&quot;&gt;Exercise 1: 20 Questions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring your finished HTML file with you to class&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;p11-checkpoint-1&quot;&gt;P1.1: Checkpoint 1&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Text chosen and submitted as a PDF for the P1.1 assignment on Blackboard&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Michael McDermott</name></author><category term="due" /><summary type="html">Discussion Board 1: Introduce yourself</summary></entry></feed>